Sanket Amin



amin.sanket.sa@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/thesanketamin



8460902001



https://sanketamin.tech/

Summary

Currently pursuing B.Tech (ECE) from Birla Vishvakarma Mahavidyalaya (B.V.M).

I am passionate of programming, particularly in language C++, Python, Java.

I have keen interest in embedded system and IoT. Have worked on software such as MATLAB, Keil, Proteus, Arduino IDE, Xilinx and many more.

During my academic career of till now, I've worked on various projects, assigned by the college, which includes Automatic Ignition Locking System, Smart Temperature Controlled System, Commercial and Residential Smart Parking System.

Experience



* Web Developer

The Sparks Foundation

May 2022 - Jun 2022 (2 months)

I had my third year summer internship in Sparks Foundation. My job role was Web Developer Intern. I worked on an project and build personal CV website using HTML, CSS, JS.

Intern

Electrofly

May 2021 - Jun 2021 (2 months)

During this period of internship, I had undergone training on electronic circuit designing tool & had also worked on various simulation & hardware part. I had done enhanced electronics components creation, circuit designing and fault finding of circuit, time management and documentation work skills. I also had hands on experience on software such as Proteus Design Suit and Arduino IDE and thus creating simulation project in the same.

VILLE IEEE SB Member

IEEE BVM SB

Mar 2019 - Dec 2020 (1 year 10 months)

Education



😡 Birla Vishvakarma Mahavidyalaya

Bachelor of Technology - BTech, Electrical, Electronics and Communications

Engineering

Aug 2019 - May 2023



Zen School

Primary, Secondary and Higher Secondary education, Higher Education/Higher Education Administration

Mar 2007 - Apr 2019 Board of Education: CBSE

Licenses & Certifications

- Student Excellence & Learning Program (SELP) National Project Implementation Unit India
- Introduction to the Internet of Things and Embedded Systems Coursera
 JAZTLSYF5E8P
- **introduction to Programming Using Python** Udemy UC-da5f77a3-0468-487a-a493-6f7b13973a71
- Python Programming LinkedIn AdlKVbBVihOtHObhtkusY683cpcT
- C# Console and Windows Form Development w/ Entity Framework Udemy UC-32f668a9-fa05-472b-8052-c2e11dd280e0

Skills

Python (Programming Language) • C++ • Java • Object-Oriented Programming (OOP) • Web Development